# **MENELIK ASFAW**

### Software Engineer | C++ | ITIL Certified

**+49172 2691340** 

@ menilik98@gmail.com

∂ https://www.linkedin.com/in/menelik-asfaw-226388140/ 
♀ Darmstadt, Hesse

#### **SUMMARY**

Technical Consultant with over 3 years of experience with Programming and Stakeholder Management skills

My variety is my strength. A progress-focused engineer with experience in AWS and software design, I offer a unique perspective to solutions engineering. My strength is my analytical skills and project management. I'm able to break down complex data to identify the correct solution, then develop a logical strategy to ensure the correct outcome is achieved. Motivated by progression, I'm constantly looking for the next opportunity to progress and develop my skills further.

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### IT Business Partner

#### **Governance Institute of Australia**

iii 08/2022 - Present ♀ Sydney, Australia

- Managed 2 projects, acceptance process, installation, deployment and sign-off with team of 2 with revenue of \$300k
- Supported 50 internal users whistle office move
- Used Microsoft system to audit documents and managed change requests then communicated changes to internal stakeholders which improved quality of delivery by 50%
- Optimized Power Automate flow to streamline the process of creating records by eliminating the need for staff to manually enter data in two separate systems, resulting in increased efficiency by 20%.

#### Technical Consultant

#### **Oscillosoft Pty Ltd**

iii 2022 - 08/2022 ♀ Sydney, Australia

- Managed support for up to 5 offshore team members to consult through large scale projects that generated over \$300k in
- Led communications across 3 clients to analyze business data and identify areas of improvement to reduce costs by 60%

#### Technical Analyst

#### **Oscillosoft Pty Ltd**

- Performed analysis and documentation on as-is capabilities for business processes to identify inefficient documentation and improve delivery time by 30%
- Gathered intelligence from team of 4 to understand needs and future growth strategy which increases growth by 30%
- Evaluated customer behavior data to understand where areas of improvement for quality and client satisfaction which increased quality by 20%
- Assisted in the development and testing of new business processes, capabilities, and supporting technologies to improve security reduced time by 30%
- Managed 5 projects, acceptance process, installation, deployment and sign-off with team of 4 with revenue of \$110k
- Supported 9 clients through customer service, and post-sales account management which generated over \$150K in revenue
- Developed deployment deliverables including internal and customer communications, and training materials for up to 50+ emplovees
- Used Google system to audit documents and managed change requests then communicated changes to 9 clients worth up to \$150K in revenue

#### STRENGTHS



#### **Analytical**

Led 3 clients to analyze their company needs and identify areas for saving opportunity which reduced costs by 60%.



#### Strategy and Growth

Used Zoho Analytics to gather data intelligence from team of 5 to identify areas of opportunity which increased growth by 30%



#### **Clear Communication**

Led over 10+ Clients on initial introductory workshops which converted 40% to projects.

### **SKILLS**

**Python ETL** atil. Communications Analytical **Zoho CRM** C++ Linux **Power BI** R **Zoho Creator Process Improvement Change Improvement** Zendesk **Zoho Desk** Jira Confluence **Zoho Analytics** 

### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Computer Science** 

**Western Sydney University, Kingswood NSW** 

**=** 02/2017 - 11/2020

Masters of Computer Science

**TU Darmstadt, Darmstadt. Hesse** 

**≐** 2023

## **CERTIFICATION**

#### **ITIL Foundation Level**

PeopleCert | Issued Apr 2022 · No Expiration Date | Credential ID GR671390467MA

#### **Learning Data Analytics**

LinkedIn | Issued Nov 2021 · No Expiration DateIssued Nov 2021 · No Expiration Date | Credential ID AVVZ-V6uHdpxuD9TiSjfZCQlulN6Credential